

JAYSON GARCIA WEB DEVELOPER

Contact

Blk 23 Lot 19 Brgy. San Lorenzo Ruiz, Taytay Rizal

+639561490771

https://hallowichig0.github.io

garciajayson502@gmail.com

Portfolio

Website:

https://hallowichig0.github.io/#portfolio

https://github.com/hallowichig0

Linkedin:

https://ph.linkedin.com/in/hallowichig0

{O}

- Wordpress (Sage, Bedrock & ACF Stoutlogic)
- Drupal
- Laravel
- PHP
- Symfony

About Me

Experienced Web Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the Information Technology industry.

Skilled in Wordpress (Roots Sage 10 + Bedrock + ACF StoutLogic), Drupal, PHP, Symfony, Twig, Blade, Javascript, Jquery, HTML 5, CSS 3, SCSS, MySQL, Responsive Web Design & Linux.

Strong Backend & Frontend skills with Associates degree focused in Information Technology.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

June 2013 - April 2017 Jose Rizal University

Work Experience

Copia Digital

January 2023 - Present

Senior WordPress Developer

- Designed, developed websites based on Figma mock-up. (Primarily using Wordpress, Laravel, PHP, Symfony, Blade, HTML 5, CSS 3, SCSS, Javascript & MySQL).
- Manage, create & update Boilerplate Project (Based on roots sage, roots bedrock & acf stoutlogic). Boilerplate project is ready to use for developer
- · Managed & configured docker for Boilerplate Project
- Created re-usable custom blocks in Boilerplate Project
- · Created custom & dynamic filters using AJAX & MVC pattern
- Used composer tool, npm, yarn, webpack to manage the plugins/modules & libraries dependencies
- Used Git and GitHub to make the creation of the website more centralized and organized.
- Used GitHub CI/CD action to deploy the codebase on different environment

- TWIG Template Engine
- Blade Template Engine
- Model View Controller (MVC)
- MySQL
- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Bootstrap
- SCSS
- Javascript
- Ajax
- jQuery
- JSON
- React JS / Next JS
- Postman
- REST API
- Git
- GitHub / GitLab / Bitbucket
- GitHub Action CI / CD
- Docker
- Composer / NPM / Yarn
- Webpack
- Laravel Mix
- Gulp JS
- Linux / Bash / Shell Scripting

CoDev

January 2023 - Present

Web Developer

- Designed, developed websites based on Figma mock-up. (Primarily using Wordpress, Laravel, PHP, Symfony, Blade, HTML 5, CSS 3, SCSS, Javascript & MySQL).
- Manage, create & update Boilerplate Project (Based on roots sage, roots bedrock & acf stoutlogic).
 Boilerplate project is ready to use for developer
- Managed & configured docker for Boilerplate Project
- Created re-usable custom blocks in Boilerplate Project
- Created custom & dynamic filters using AJAX & MVC pattern
- Used composer tool, npm, yarn, webpack to manage the plugins/modules & libraries dependencies
- Used Git and GitHub to make the creation of the website more centralized and organized.
- Used GitHub CI/CD action to deploy the codebase on different environment

Yondu, Inc.

July 2022 - January 2023

Software Engineer II

- Integrated cmsable component for New GlobeOne
- Exposed cmsable component REST API for New GlobeOne
- Created custom DateTimePicker for cmsable schedule
- POST REST API to other platform server

Halcyon Digital Media Design Inc.

May 2019 - July 2022

Web Developer

- Designed, developed websites based on Adobe XD & Figma mock-up. (Primarily using Drupal, Wordpress, Laravel, PHP, Symfony, TWIG, Blade, HTML 5, CSS 3, SASS, Javascript & MySQL).
- Integrated Custom Theme in every wordpress & drupal projects. (I used my own boilerplate setup).
- Integrated sage 10 theme & bedrock in all wordpress projects.
- Used composer tool, npm, yarn & gulp js to manage the plugins/modules & libraries dependencies.
- Used Git and GitHub to make the creation of the website more centralized and organized.

Evervue Philippines Inc.

September 2018 - March 2019

Web Developer

- Designed, developed websites. (Primarily using WORDPRESS, HTML, CSS, SASS, PHP, JAVASCRIPT & MYSQL).
- Designed and programmmed online e-commerce and commercial website for electronic product of Evervue Philippines Inc.
- Integrated Custom Theme Backend. Used Git and GitLab to make the creation of the website more centralized and organized.
- Resolved program error and other technical issues by leveraging strengths in coding, debugging and integration testing.
- Supported users in managing, maintaining, access server and troubleshooting for both local area networks and hardware.
- Set up equipment for employees, including installing TCP/IP, cables, software and hardware.

GlobeTek Science Foundation Inc.

April 2017- August 2018

Web Developer

- Designed, developed websites. (Primarily using HTML, CSS, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MYSQL & WORDPRESS).
- Designed and programmed online e-commerce website for both retail product and online restaurant for GlobeTek Science Foundation Inc.
- Designed and programmed mobile application for the Earth Fashion Café online restaurant.
- Programmed E-Learning System for the school to view both the grades and files of both the students and teachers. The teacher could input the grades of each students in into system.
- Resolved program error and other technical issues by leveraging strengths in coding, debugging and integration testing.
- Structure and 3D modeling of store replica and schematics using sketch up.